

### Curriculum Vitae for Guttorm Kvaal

### Personal information

Address: Trondheimsveien 5D E-mail: guttorm@xal.no

0560 Oslo Phone: +47 40468642 24/08/1992 Nationality: Norwegian

# **Summary**

Born:

I am a curious person with an interest and enthusiasm for technology and problem solving. I submitted my master's thesis summer 2017 in the field of Computational Science and Engineering at the University of Oslo / Simula. In my work I performed numerical simulations of micro-particles inhaled into the human respiratory system. This involved writing Python scripts and working with open-source solutions and libraries, as well as performing data analysis and supercomputer simulations. My academic background involves a combination of mathematics and programming, together with insights in physics and fluid mechanics. During my studies I have developed my professional experience through part-time and holiday positions within teaching and customer service.

#### Technical skills

Frameworks Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, FEniCS

Languages Python

Tools Git, Linux, Ansys ICEM, Paraview

#### **Education**

2015 - 2017 Master's Degree in Computational Science and Engineering at the

University of Oslo

2012 – 2015 Bachelors's Degree in Physics at the University of Oslo

## **Professional experience**

2017 –	Consultant, Expert Analytics
2016 - 2017	Administration Assistant, Simula
2016	Teachers Assistant, Department of Informatics, University of Oslo
2015 - 2016	Customer Service Cosultant, Nokas Cash Handling
2011 – 2012	Integration Sales, Klarna

### Languages

English Fluent Norwegian Native

#### Personal skills

Applied Analyse and solve problems using mathematical methods and com-

Mathematics puter programming

Customer Communicate and coordinate with customers and third parties during

Service hectic situations

#### Some interests and hobbies

Indoor Cooking, history

Outdoor Mountainbiking, alpine, hiking

# **Extended descriptions of selected projects**

Activity Numerical Simulations of Pharmaceutical Particles Depositing in the

Human Respiratory System, Verification and Validation of a Virtual

Laboratory

Period 2016 - 2017 Role Master student

Staffing 1

Description The aim of my master's thesis was to investigate the link between size

and location of deposition of micro-particles inhaled into the human respiratory system. By combining Python scripts and open-source solutions I was able to perform accurate simulations and estimate a

range of partice sizes suitable for delivering inhalation medicine.

Tools Python, FEniCS, Oasis, Ansys ICEM, Paraview